SANDEEP SHUKLA () Featured

Software Development,Requirement Gathering,Application Development,Requirement Analysis,Application Programming,Manual Testing,C#,JavaScript,Jquery,ASP.Net,Entity Framework,MVC,WCF,MS SQL Server,LINQy,SDK.



Current Designation: Associate Technical Lead Total Experience: 8 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Ebix Software India Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Noida Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computer Sc.]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Noida, Gurgaon

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Other

Key Skills: Software Development, Requirement Gathering, Application Development, Requirement Analysis, Application

Programming, Manual Testing, C#, JavaScript, Jquery, ASP. Net, Entity Framework, MVC, WCF, MS SQL

Server, LINQ, Ajax, SAP B1

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 17-Nov-20 Last Modified: 17-Nov-20

Summary

Communicate timely updates and status of projects, Manual testing, Coding Adherence to quality standards, client interaction. Providing on job training to sub-ordinates, onsite implementation experience with good communication skills. Currently deputed at Ebix India Pvt. Ltd., Noida as Sr. .Net Developer. Proficient in programming with C#.Net, ASP.Net, Windows Application, n- Tier Architecture, MS SQL Server, Crystal Report, Microsoft Reporting, JavaScript, jquery, SSRS Report, Linq, Entity Framework, MVC 4.0, WCF, Angular JS2 Sound knowledge of object oriented programming (OOPS). Worked on the client places and gain the user requirements

Work Experience

Ebix Software India as Associate Technical Lead Jan 2019 to Till Date

Kabeer Consulting Pvt Ltd as Senior Technical Consultant

Dec 2017 to Dec 2018

UI design in SAP, Creating database in sql through c# code, creating crystel report in SAP, Bug fixing in existing add on applications, writing sql queries.

Velocis Systems Pvt Ltd as Team Lead- Application Programming

Mar 2017 to Aug 2017

Key Projects handled Project #1:Public Enterprises Survey

PESurvey

Description PESurvey application is for Department of public enterprises to survey public companies. Company?s employees review details like how many reviewed,how many fit for retention are involved in this application.

Providing data to survey department regarding these public companies.

Role Requirement Analysis, Team coordination(Technical)
Environment Asp.Net,C#,javascript,AngularJs2,RDLC Report

Contribution Worked as a part of Development team. Created documents.

Accenture Services Pvt Ltd as Analyst

Jun 2014 to Jan 2017

Key Projects handled Project #1:mDart

mDart

Description mDart is a monitoring tool available to senior managers of Accenture across Global Delivery Centers. It is primarily used to monitor health of the projects through various metrics. It displays the status of projects through interactive graphs, charts and powerful reporting tool. It gathers the data from other components like cDart, DMS etc. and presents a centralized and comprehensive analysis including key metrics. The senior managers who have access to the system can look at the reports and identify possible points which need attention or correction with respect to the project. Role Requirement Analysis, Team coordination(Technical)

Environment Asp.Net,C#,html,javascript,jquery,Ajax,SSRS Report

Contribution *jQuery111007572289284974834_1536555464859?Worked as a part of Development team.

*???Created documents.

Project #2:Application Modernization

Application Modernization

Description In this project there are some existing HP projects running on normal server. We are migrating those application on cloud server in different environment like development, testing and production servers. In this we take care of load balancing, clustering, SSL certificate etc.

Role Requirement Analysis, Team coordination(Technical)

Environment MS SQL Server 2010, Asp. Net

Contribution Worked as a part of Development team.

Created documents.

Chetu India Pvt Ltd as Software Engineer

May 2013 to Jun 2014

ConveyHealth

Description Islandluck is a mobile application for slot gaming. In this application we play the game on different pay lines and player will win the game when that pay line is according to the pay line in the payout table. In this game there is a scatter symbol that is considered a symbol for payout table. In this game there are two buttons spin and free spin. When we click spin amount

will be deducted according to paylines and line bet. When we click free spin amount will not deduct. We also win free spins on clicking spin button.

Role Requirement Analysis, Team coordination(Technical)

Environment MS SQL Server 2010, Asp. Net, Entity frame work, Linq, MVC 4.0

Contribution Worked as a part of Development team.

Created documents.

Project #2: CodeSmart Group

CodeSmartGroup

Description Codesmart group is a application for group of hospitals. In this application staff assignment, facility settings are done. Diagnosis and procedures are managed through this application. In this application there are different roles like corp admin, admin, cds etc. by which we decide accessibility.

Role Requirement Analysis, Team coordination(Technical)

Environment MS SQL Server 2008 R2, Entity Framework, Linq

Contribution Worked as a part of Development team.

Created documents.

Project #3: ConveyHealth

ConveyHealth

Description Actually Convey Health is a mediclaim Insurance Company. File processing system between bank and company is in BAI format. This BAI format is divided into different tables of payment processing system. In this there are different procedures for file parsing, validation, autoposting and file approval

Role Requirement Analysis, Team coordination(Technical)

Environment MS SQL Server 2010

Contribution Worked as a part of Development team.

Created documents.

Stowe Research India Pvt. Ltd. as Software Engineer

May 2011 to Mar 2013

Creating modules using c#,sql server,java script,jquery etc.Creating report in microsoft reporting service(rdlc)

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Sc.) from Dr. R.M.L. Avadh University in 2005

IT Skills

2007 2007 2007 2007 2007 2007	Experience 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007 2007 2007 2007	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007 2007 2007	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	. , , , , ,
	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	. ,
	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2007	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2016	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2020	6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
2018	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
	2007 2007 2007 2016 2020 2020

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Countries: India

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time